stubhub.co.uk 2014-10-19

# 

This User Privacy Notice (" **Privacy Notice** ") applies to your use of the www.stubhub.co.uk website, our mobile applications, tools and all associated services (collectively the " **Marketplace Services** ") provided by StubHub Europe S.à.r.l., eBay International AG or StubHub Inc. (collectively " **StubHub** ", your data controller for all Marketplace Services) in accordance with the Marketplace Services User Agreement (" **User Agreement** ").

If you use the Marketplace Services to list and sell tickets (in this capacity " **Seller** ") this Privacy Notice also applies to your use of the payment processing services (" **Payment Services** ") provided to you by StubHub Services S.à.r.l. (" **StubHub Services** ", your data controller for all Payment Services) in accordance with the Payment Services Agreement for Sellers (" **Payment Services Agreement** ").

Please read the summary below and click on the "Learn more" link in each section for more details on a particular topic.

This Privacy Notice is effective on 15 October 2014 for all current users and upon registration for new users. We may amend this Privacy Notice by providing existing users with 30 days’ advance notice. We will post any changes on this website. Additionally, we will notify you via email of any material changes to this Privacy Notice. Your continued use of the Marketplace Services and/or Payment Services after the end of the 30 days’ notice period indicates your acceptance of the amended Privacy Notice.

**Scope and Consent**

This Privacy Notice describes your privacy rights regarding our collection, use, disclosure, retention and protection of your personal information. It applies to any StubHub site where this Privacy Notice appears in the footer, and to any Marketplace Services (as defined above) where this Privacy Notice is referenced, regardless of how you access or use them, including through mobile devices.

This Privacy Notice also applies to your use of the Payment Services (as defined above) provided to you by StubHub Services in conjunction with your use of the Marketplace Services as a Seller.

By using our Services and/or registering for an account with us, you are accepting the terms of this Privacy Notice and you are consenting to our collection, use, disclosure and retention of your personal information as described in this Privacy Notice and in our User Agreement and Payment Services Agreement. If you do not provide the information we require, we may not be able to provide all our Services to you.

**Controlling and Processing Parties for Marketplace Services**

If you reside within the European Union, your data controller for all Marketplace Services is StubHub Europe S.à r.l., 22-24 Boulevard Royal, L-2449, Luxembourg. If you reside within the United States your data controller for all Marketplace Services is StubHub, Inc., 199 Fremont Street, Floor 4, San Francisco, CA 94105, USA. If you reside elsewhere your data controller for all Marketplace Services is eBay International AG, Helvetiastrasse 15/17, 3005, Bern, Switzerland. Your data controller is responsible for the processing of your personal information in accordance with our global privacy standards and can transfer data to StubHub Europe S.à r.l., StubHub Services S.à.r.l., StubHub Inc., eBay International AG and elsewhere in the world eBay Inc. has facilities. We may store and process your personal information on our computers in the US and elsewhere in the world where our data centres are located.

**Controlling and Processing Parties for Payment Services**

Irrespective of your place of residence if you use our Marketplace Services to list and sell tickets as a Seller, your data controller for Payment Services provided to you in accordance with the Payment Services Agreement is StubHub Services S.à.r.l., 22-24 Boulevard Royal, L-2449 Luxembourg. StubHub Services is responsible for the processing of your personal information in accordance with our global privacy standards and can transfer data to StubHub Europe S.à r.l., StubHub Inc., eBay International AG, PayPal (Europe) S.à r.l. et Cie, S.C.A. and elsewhere in the world eBay Inc. has facilities and to those data recipients referred to in the Payment Services Agreement. We may store and process your personal information on our computers in the US and elsewhere in the world where our data centres are located.

**Personal Information**

"Personal information" is information that can be associated with a specific person and could be used to identify that specific person whether from that data alone or from that data in combination with other information that StubHub has or is likely to have access to. We do not consider personal information to include information that has been made anonymous or aggregated so that it can no longer be used, whether in combination with other information or otherwise, to identify a specific person.  
  
**Global Privacy Standards**

Our parent company eBay Inc. has established global privacy standards for all eBay Inc. companies known as our Binding Corporate Rules (BCRs). They are our commitment to protect your personal information and honour our privacy obligations regardless of where your personal information is collected, processed or stored. Our BCRs have been approved by a number of European Union privacy regulators. More information about our BCRs and our global privacy practices and principles, including information on how to contact us, is available at our [eBay Privacy Centre](http://www.ebayprivacycenter.com/privacy).  
  
**Collection**

We collect personal information from you and the devices (including mobile devices) you use to access or use our Services. This personal information we collect includes, but is not limited to, personal information of the kinds described below:

**Personal information you give us when you use our Services**

**For Marketplace Services**

  * Information you provide us when registering with StubHub, which may include name, physical address, email address, telephone and/or mobile phone number, business seller information, tax identification number;
  * Financial information such PayPal account information, credit card, debit card or bank account information;
  * Transactional information based on your activities on our sites and through our Services (such as information on your buying and selling activity, ticket information and other content you generate or that relates to your account);
  * Postage, billing and other information you provide to purchase or list a ticket, as well as, where postal services are provided through one of our programmes, additional relevant postage information (such as tracking updates) provided by the chosen postal partner;
  * Information provided in the context of user ratings and reviews, chats, dispute resolution, correspondence through our sites and Services, or correspondence sent to us;
  * Additional information you may be asked to provide in order to verify your or your business’ identity or other information pertaining to your account or listings. Such information may include name and address of legal representatives and beneficial owners, date of birth, nationality, and copies of your passport and/or other identification documents.

**For Payment Services**

  * Information you provide us when registering with StubHub Services, which may include name, physical address, email address, telephone and/or mobile phone number, business seller information, tax identification number;
  * Financial information such PayPal account information, credit card, debit card or bank account information and other information required to process your payments;
  * Payment transaction information;
  * Additional information that may be necessary to verify your or your business’ identity and comply with anti-money laundering regulations or similar laws. Such information may include the name and address of legal representatives and beneficial owners, date of birth, nationality, articles of association, and copies of your passport and/or other identification documents.

**Personal information we collect automatically when you use our Services**

We also collect information about your interaction with our sites and Services, advertising (Marketplace Services only) or e-mail communications. This is typically information we receive from your computer or other devices, including your mobile devices.

  * Device ID or unique identifier, device type, ID for Advertising, unique device token;
  * For Marketplace Services only: Geo-location information, including location information from your mobile device. Keep in mind that:
    * Most mobile devices allow you to control or disable the use of location services in the device's settings' menu.
    * You may also be presented with an additional notice explaining any additional information we may collect from you that is not listed in this notice.
  * Computer and connection information;
  * Statistics on page views, traffic to and from the sites, referral URL, ad data, IP address, browsing history and web log information.

**Personal information we collect using Cookies, Web Beacons and Similar Technologies**

We use cookies, web beacons, unique identifiers, and similar technologies to provide and improve our Services and personalised advertising and marketing (Marketplace Services only) and to provide a safer and personalised experience on our sites. We collect information about the pages you view, the links you click and other actions you take on our Services, or within our advertising or email content. For more information about our use of these technologies and how to control them, see our notice on Cookies, Web Beacons and Similar Technologies.

**Personal information from other sources**

  * We may supplement the information we collect from you with information from third parties and add it to your account information. This may include demographic information that is publically available, additional contact information and other information required to verify your or your business’ identity, credit check information and information from credit bureaus (Payment Services only), as authorised by you or permitted by law. We may combine information you give us with information we collect from other sources and use it for the purposes disclosed in this Privacy Notice.
  * For Marketplace Services only: We may allow you to share information with third party social media sites, or use social media sites or other sites to create or connect to your account. Those social media sites may give us access to certain personal information stored by them (e.g. content viewed and information about the advertisements within the content you have been shown or may have clicked on etc.). You can control the personal information you allow us to have access to through the privacy settings on that third party site and the permissions you give us when you grant us access. By associating an account managed by a third party with your account and authorising StubHub to have access to this information, you agree that StubHub may collect, use and store the information provided by these sites in accordance with this Privacy Notice.
  * If you give us personal information about someone else, you must do so only with their consent. You agree to inform them that we have collected their personal information and tell them how we collect, use and disclose the personal information.

**Use and Retention**

We use the personal information we collect to operate, improve and personalise our Services, to contact you and provide you customer service, customise our advertising and marketing, to detect, prevent and mitigate fraudulent or illegal activities and to comply with our legal obligations. You agree that we may use your personal information as follows:

**Operate, improve and personalise our Services**

  * Provide you use of and access to our Services;
  * Process payments for Sellers;
  * Give you access to your purchase and sales history, payment transaction history, internal email and other features and functionalities;
  * Customise, measure and improve our Services;
  * Provide other services requested by you as described when we collect the information;
  * Provide you with location based services, such as advertising, search results, and other personalised content using geo-location information (Marketplace Services only).

**Contact you and provide you with customer service**

  * Provide customer support you request for our Services or for the products offered by members of our corporate family;
  * Contact you, either via email or telephone (including using auto-dialled or pre-recorded messages), text (SMS) messages (if applicable) as authorised by you to provide you with information regarding your listings, sales, purchases or payment transactions, resolve disputes, collect fees, and troubleshoot problems with your account or our Services and for other purposes authorised by law and consistent with this Privacy Notice.

**Customise our advertising and marketing communications with you (Marketplace Services only)**

  * Customise, measure, and improve our content and advertising based on your ad customisation preferences;
  * Deliver targeted marketing about our services and those of our corporate family, service updates and promotional offers either via email, telephone (including using auto-dialled or pre-recorded messages), text (SMS) messages, or postal mail, based on your communication preferences.

**Detect, Prevent and Mitigate Fraudulent or Illegal Activities**

  * Prevent, detect, investigate and report fraud, security breaches, potentially prohibited or illegal activities;
  * Protect the security or integrity of our sites and Services;
  * Comply with anti-money laundering obligations (Payment Services only);
  * Sanctions list scanning (Payment Services only);
  * Enforce our User Agreement, Payment Services Agreement or other applicable policies;
  * Compare the personal information you provide for accuracy, and verify it with information provided by third parties as necessary.

**Other**

  * For accounting and litigation purposes;
  * To check your creditworthiness and solvency (Payment Services only).

We retain your personal information as long as it is necessary and relevant for our operations. In general, personal information from closed accounts will be deleted or rendered anonymous as soon as reasonably possibly after the account is closed or deactivated. Under certain circumstances we may retain personal information from closed accounts to prevent fraud, collect any fees owed, resolve disputes, troubleshoot problems, assist with any investigation, enforce our User Agreement or Payment Services Agreement, comply with applicable legal data retention obligations and take other actions permitted by law. After it is no longer necessary for us to retain your personal information, we will dispose of it in a secure manner according to our data retention and deletion policies.  
  
**Choice**

You have a choice about how we use your personal information to communicate with you, send you marketing information (Marketplace Services only), and provide you with customised and relevant advertising (Marketplace Services only).

**Communication Preferences**

You can control how and when you want to receive notifications from StubHub about your buying and selling activities and the methods by which we may contact you from the Communication Settings section within your account. You can also choose which newsletters and promotions you want to receive.

**Marketing**

We do not sell or rent your personal information to third parties for their marketing purposes without your explicit consent. If you do not wish to receive marketing communications from us, you can unsubscribe from the link in the email you received, change your Communication Preferences within your Account or indicate your preferences within the direct communication from us.

**Advertising**

We do not allow third parties to track or collect your personal information on our sites for their own advertising purposes without your explicit consent. If you do not wish to participate in our ad-customisation programmes, you can opt-out by following the directions provided within the applicable advertisement. The effect of an opt-out will be to stop targeted advertising, but it will still allow the collection of usage data for certain purposes (e.g. research, analytics and internal online services operation purposes).

If you withdraw your consent for the use or disclosure of your personal information for the other purposes set out in this Privacy Notice you may not have access to all of our Services and we might not be able to provide you all of the Services and customer support offered to our users and authorised under this Privacy Notice and our User Agreement.  
  
**Access**

We take steps to ensure that the personal information we collect is accurate and up to date, and that you have the ability to access or correct it.

  * You can see, review and change most of your personal information by signing on to your account. Please update your personal information immediately if it changes or is inaccurate.
  * Once you make a public posting, you may not be able to change or remove it. Upon your request, we will close your account and remove your personal information from view as soon as reasonably possible, based on your account activity and in accordance with applicable law.
  * We will honour any statutory right you might have to access, modify or erase your personal information. You can contact [Customer Service](https://www.stubhub.co.uk/help/?tab=#contactus) to request access. Where you have a legal right to request access or request the correction of information, we can still withhold that access or decline to correct information in some cases in accordance with applicable law, but will give you reasons if we do so.

**Disclosure**

We disclose personal information to respond to legal requirements, enforce our policies, respond to claims that a listing or other content violates the rights of others, or protect the rights, property or safety of any member of the eBay Inc. corporate family, other users or third parties. Such information will be disclosed only in accordance with applicable laws and regulations (such as professional secrecy obligations). We minimise the amount of personal information we share to what is directly relevant and necessary to accomplish the specified purpose. As stated above, we do not disclose your personal information to third parties for their marketing purposes without your explicit consent.

We may share your personal information with:

  * [Members of the eBay Inc. corporate family](http://www.ebayprivacycenter.com/about-us/corporate-family)to provide joint content and services (like registration, transactions and customer support), to help detect and prevent potentially illegal acts and violations of our policies, to guide decisions about their products, sites, applications, tools, services and communications and to provide customised advertising. Members of our corporate family may use this information to send you marketing communications only if you have consented to their services and will use your personal information in compliance with their respective privacy policies and our global privacy standards.
  * Third party service providers, payment processors and financial institutions under contract who help with our business operations (such as, but not limited to, fraud detection and investigations, identity verification services, payment processing, bill collection, affiliate and rewards programmes, website operations, fulfilment and delivery services or ticket cancellation and reissue services).
  * Co-brand partners for certain sites, events or listings. When we identify a co-brand partner for a site, event or listing, you agree that we may share contact information and transaction data (excluding financial information) with that partner. Information shared with a co-brand partner is subject to their privacy policy. We do not control the privacy policies of co-brand partners and we encourage you to review their privacy policies.
  * Marketing partners for certain sites, events or listings where you agree during checkout that you would like your information shared for their marketing purposes. We may share your contact information and transaction data (excluding financial information) with the marketing partner identified in checkout. Information shared with a marketing partner is subject to their privacy policy. We do not control the privacy policies of marketing partners and we encourage you to review their privacy policies.
  * Other StubHub users, whether located in your country of residence or outside of your country of residence, as required for them to complete a transaction. For example, when you purchase a ticket, the Seller may view your delivery address to complete the transaction.
  * Other third parties to whom you explicitly ask us to send your information (or about whom you are otherwise explicitly notified and consent to when using a specific service).
  * Local and foreign law enforcement or regulatory agencies, other government officials or authorised third-parties, in response to a verified request relating to a criminal investigation (i.e. a subpoena, court order or substantially similar legal procedure) or alleged illegal activity or any other activity that may expose us, you, or any other StubHub user to legal liability. In such events, we will disclose information relevant and necessary to the investigation or inquiry, such as name, address, telephone number, email address, IP address, fraud complaints, sales and/or purchase history or payment transaction history.
  * Credit bureaus to which we might report information about your account, including information on late fee payments, missed fee payments or other defaults on your account that may be reflected in your credit report, as allowed by applicable law. For Payment Services only we may share information about you in order to check your creditworthiness and solvency.

While we use contractual and other measures to ensure protection of personal information, the laws and regulations relating to privacy and personal information protection in other jurisdictions may not be the same as, or similar to, your local privacy laws. The governments, courts, law enforcement or regulatory agencies in these other jurisdictions may be able to request disclosure of personal information through the laws of these countries. In an effort to respect your privacy, we will not otherwise disclose your personal information to law enforcement, other government officials, or other third parties without a subpoena, court order or substantially similar legal procedure, except when we believe in good faith that the disclosure of information is necessary to prevent imminent physical harm, financial loss or to report potentially illegal or fraudulent activity.

If we were to merge with or be acquired by another company, we may share information with them in accordance with our Global Privacy Standards. Should such an event occur, we will require that the new combined entity follow this Privacy Notice with respect to your personal information. If your personal information will be used or disclosed for any purposes not covered in this Privacy Notice, you will receive prior notification of the use of your personal information for the new purposes.  
  
**Security**

We protect your information using technical and administrative security measures to reduce the risks of loss, misuse, unauthorised access, disclosure and alteration. Some of the safeguards we use are firewalls and data encryption, physical access controls to our data centres, and information access authorisation controls.  
  
**Important Information**

There are just a few more pieces of important privacy information related to your use of our Services that we need to cover:

**Using information obtained on StubHub**

Other users have access to the information you share on StubHub (e.g. listings, ratings and reviews, business seller information). To help protect the privacy of our users, we allow only limited access to other users’ contact, delivery and financial information as necessary to facilitate ticket purchases, sales and payment transactions. You may only use the personal information that you have access to for StubHub transaction-related purposes, for using services offered through StubHub (such as delivery services) and for purposes expressly consented by the user to whom the information relates. Using personal information that you have access to for any other purpose is a violation of our policies.

**Unwanted or threatening email**

Sending unwanted or threatening email is against our policies and constitutes a violation of our User Agreement. To report StubHub-related spam or spoof emails please forward the email to [safety@stubhub.co.uk](mailto:safety@stubhub.co.uk).

**Children's Privacy**

Our websites are general audience websites, and our Services are not intended for users under the age of 18. We do not knowingly collect personal information from users in this age group.

**Third Party Privacy Practices**

This Privacy Notice addresses only the use and disclosure of personal information we collect from you. If you disclose your information to others, their privacy notices and practices will apply. We cannot guarantee the privacy or security of your information once you provide it to a third party and we encourage you to evaluate the privacy and security policies of any third party before entering into a transaction and choosing to share your information.  
  
**Questions or Complaints**

If you have questions or concerns about this Privacy Notice or our global privacy or information handling processes, you can contact Customer Service or write to your data controller within the European Union:

  * For Marketplace Services: StubHub Europe S.à.r.l. – Privacy Notice Requests, 22-24 Boulevard Royal, L-2449 Luxembourg.
  * For Payment Services: StubHub Services S.à r.l. – Privacy Notice Requests, 22-24 Boulevard Royal, L-2449 Luxembourg.

If you do not feel satisfied with our response, you can always contact your local data protection authority or the [Commission Nationale pour la Protection des Données](http://www.cnpd.public.lu/fr/support/contact/index.php) in Luxembourg directly.

You can also find more information on our global privacy processes and how to contact us at our [eBay Privacy Centre](http://www.ebayprivacycenter.com/about-us).
